你还有牙膏吗
Do you have any toothpaste left?
没了
No,
因为两周以来有个人每天都在借用
'cause someone's been borrowing it every day for two weeks.
卡尔
Carl.
怎么了  丹妮斯说是体育课
What? Denise says it's PT.
我听不见  出来
I can't hear you. Come on out.
怎么了
What?
丹妮斯说是体育课
Denise says this is PT.
-你听见了  -是的
- You heard me. - Yeah.
该给你换绷带了
It's time to change your bandage.
我需要借点牙膏
And I need to borrow some toothpaste.
好吧  但我没牙膏了
Okay, but I'm out of toothpaste.
-再见  爸爸  -回头见
- Bye, Dad. - I'll see you later.
来吧  亲爱的
Come on, sweetheart.
-你出去后会没事的  -我们看吧
- You be good out there. - Yeah, we'll see.
谢谢你
And thank you.
绿薄荷和小苏打  那是我最爱的
Spearmint and baking soda. That's my favorite.
等我拿到就给你
Soon as I get it, you will.
-你好  -怎么了
- Hey. - Yes?
这底下的东西
This thing at the bottom right here.
你是说饮料  对吧
You're talking about the drink, right?
是的  但是
I am, but...
这不是药品
It's not medical.
没错  我把重要的东西和那个划线分开了
No, I drew a line between the important stuff and that.
我只是想着  如果你看见就带点
I just figured, if you saw it.
好
All right.
跟药品有关的都是优先考虑的
Anything remotely medical is a priority.
还有食物  也许比药更重要
And food, maybe even food before medicine,
还有汽油  电池  儿童书籍  衣服
and gas or batteries or books for the kids or clothes is just--
如果你看见了  如果它碰巧
if you see it, if it just happens to,
也在那里
you know, be right there.
你喜欢喝  对吧
You like it, right?
不  我不喝泡泡水
No, I don't drink pop.
泡泡水是什么
What the hell's pop?
我来自俄亥俄州
Oh, I'm originally from Ohio.
你为什么想要
Why you want it?
塔拉好像说梦话说到了
Tara was talking about it in her sleep, I think.
她要么喜欢  要么不喜欢
Either she likes it or she doesn't,
但如果她喜欢  这会是个很棒的惊喜
but if she likes it, it'd be a really nice surprise.
我不擅长这种事
I'm not good with that kind of stuff,
她和希斯要出去两周
and she and Heath are going on that two-week run.
我觉得这是个不错的临别礼物
I just thought it'd be a nice going-away present.
不用特别费心
Just, uh, don't go out of your way.
如果这会给你带来麻烦
And if it gives you any trouble...
不会的
I won't.
好  很好  因为这不重要
Okay, good, 'cause it's not important.
我该说清楚的  而不是只划条线
I should've said so instead of just drawing a line.
知道了
Got it.
(铭记于心)
我在地图上标出了一些农产品供给点
I mapped out some of the agricultural supply places in the area.
就算已经被清空了
Even if they've been cleaned out,
我觉得高粱肯定没人碰
my bet is that the Sorghum would be untouched.
那是一种严重被低估的粮食
Now, that there is a criminally underrated grain
可以改变我们的生活
that could change the game
让粮食储备从少得可怜变成满满当当
with our food situation from scary to hunky-dunky.
我是在说它的生命力  耐旱性
I'm talking standability, drought tolerance,
转为秸秆的比例  都是谷物中最高的
grain-to-stover ratio that is the envy of all corns.
考虑一下吧
Think about it.
-谢了  -不用
- Thanks. - All right.
好吧
Okay.
今天是个好日子
Today's the day.
我们会找到食物  也许还能找到一些人
We're gonna find food, maybe some people.
按概率来说也该遇到好事了
The law of averages has gotta catch up.
我可不敢确定  我们几周都没碰到人了
I don't know. We ain't seen nobody for weeks.
也许我们什么人也碰不到
Maybe we ain't gonna find nobody.
也许那是件好事
Maybe that's a good thing.
别
Don't.
求你别放
Please don't.
∮ 把它们从家里引开 ∮
∮ Draws 'em away from home! ∮
《行尸走肉》
这段时间你到哪去了
Where have you been?
什么
What?
我一直没看见你
I never see you.
大家这几周都在努力工作
Everybody's been working for weeks
重建这地方
to get this place back together
而你却不见人影
and you just disappear.
-你整天都待在房间里吗  -不是
- Do you sit in your room all day? - No.
那你去哪里了
Then where'd you go?
没去哪里
Nowhere.
你帮格伦回家
You helped Glenn get home.
我在那个哨岗上时你也帮了我
You helped me when I was up in that guard post.
所以呢
Yeah?
所以也许比起"没去哪里"
So maybe there are better places
你有更好的去处
for you to go than just nowhere.
我就在这里
I'm around.
可以来找我聊聊
Come talk to me.
(高粱)
等等
Hey, hold up.
小心为上
It's best to be safe.
-掩护我  -好
- You cover it? - Yeah.
安全
Yeah, we're good.
再来一次吗
One more time?
没上锁
It ain't locked.
瞧瞧
Well, how about that?
概率
The law of averages.
是啊
Yep.
我们把这车发动起来
Let's get this thing going,
带上装备  晚点再回来取车
grab our gear, come back for the car later.
走另一条路回去
Take another way back.
看看能不能遇上什么
See what we can see.
你觉得这车能发动吗
Think it'll start?
我觉得能
Yeah, I do.
高粱
Sorghum.
喂  过来帮个忙
Yo, give me a hand with this.
我们把它翻过来
Let's flip it over.
我觉得我们翻不过来
I don't think we got it.
我有个主意
I got an idea.
是汽水和糖果  要这么麻烦吗
It's soda and candy. Why the trouble?
一点也不麻烦
It wasn't any trouble.
后退  马上
Back up! Now!
举起手来
Keep 'em up!
放松点  伙计们
Whoa, easy, guys.
我只是在躲行尸
I was just running from the dead.
有多少只
How many?
十只  也许更多
10, maybe more.
我不想冒险
I'm not risking it.
只要到达两位数  我就会跑
Once it gets to double digits, I start running.
在哪里
Where?
后面大约半英里
About a half a mile back.
它们正朝这边来
They're headed this way.
你们大概有十一分钟吧
You probably have about 11 minutes.
好吧  谢谢你告诉我们
Okay, thanks for letting us know.
当然
Yeah.
它们数量比我们多  对吧
There's more of them than us, right?
我们必须团结起来
Gotta stick together.
对吗
Right?
你们有营地吗
You have a camp?
没有
No.
你呢
Do you?
没有
No.
很抱歉撞到你
Sorry for running into you.
现在我得走了
I'm gonna go now.
如果这就是新世界  希望你们过得还好
If this is the next world, I hope it's good to you guys.
我是瑞克  这是达里尔
I'm Rick. This is Daryl.
你叫什么
What's your name?
保罗·罗维
Paul Rovia.
但朋友们一般都叫我耶稣
But my friends used to call me Jesus.
你们随意
Your pick.
你说你没有营地
You said you didn't have a camp.
你是独自一人吗
You on your own?
是的
Yeah.
但是  最好别打什么歪主意
But, still, best not to try anything.
也最好别做不自量力的威胁
Best not to make threats you can't keep, either.
没错
Exactly.
-你杀过多少...  -不  不要这家伙
- How many walkers... - No, not this guy.
你杀过多少行尸
How many walkers have you killed?
抱歉  我得逃了  你们也应该快逃
Sorry, gotta run. You should, too.
你们大概还有七分钟
Think you've got about seven minutes.
你干嘛问他
What the hell was that?
他很干净
He was clean.
他的胡子修过
His beard, it was trimmed.
肯定有名堂
There's more going on there.
他也没有枪
He didn't have a gun, either.
我们可以跟踪他  观察一下
We could track him, watch him for a while,
多了解一些
get to know more.
看看他是不是真的独自一人
See if he's really alone.
也许带他回去
Maybe bring him back.
才不要  这家伙管自己叫耶稣
Nah, guy calls himself Jesus.
鞭炮
Firecrackers.
-该死  -妈的
- Hell. - Shit.
他把你的钥匙偷走了  对吧
He swiped your keys, didn't he?
该死
Shit!
抱歉啦
Sorry!
该死
Shit.
来吧
Come on.
来啊
我来
I got him.
你觉得我对付不了它吗
You think I couldn't get it?
你可以的
You could've.
但我有刀
I have a sword.
你在这干什么
What are you doing out here?
我站岗时看到有人进入了树林
I was on guard. I saw someone was in the woods.
你跑出来干什么
What are you doing out here?
我轮班结束后散散步
I walk after my shifts.
我这样做已经有段时间了
I've been doing it for a while.
你是第一个注意到的
You're the first one to notice.
那为什么带铲子
Why the shovel?
我继续散步了
I'm gonna keep walking now.
我陪你一起
I'm gonna come with you.
好啊
That's okay.
你妈妈曾要我搞清楚
Your mom told me I had to figure out what I want...
一辈子想要什么
for my whole life.
你搞清楚了吗
Have you?
我还在努力
I'm working up to it.
现在我只想知道
Right now I just want to find out
她儿子为什么要带着铲子在树林里游荡
why her son's wandering around the woods with a shovel.
看
Look.
写的什么
What's it say?
全湿了
It got wet.
看不清了
It's all gone.
走吧
Come on.
看上去没那么旧
It doesn't look that old.
是吗
Yeah?
我们虽然看不清写的是什么
I mean, we can't read what they wrote,but ...
但是有人这样做  证明了一件事
just by doing this, they're saying something.
什么事
What?
我们并不孤独
"We're not alone."
我们知道这一点  我们亲眼见过
We knew that. We saw it.
还死了人
People died.
我们为什么来这
Why are we coming out here?
因为我们是孩子
'Cause we're kids.
孩子就喜欢到处玩
It's what they do.
我们不是孩子了
We're not kids.
这是医生的特别要求
This was a special request from the doctor.
她要什么都行
Whatever she wants.
她救了卡尔的命
She saved Carl's life.
我们之前不了解她  后来发现她还不错
We didn't know her, and she turned out to be all right.
如果外面还有人
If there's still people out here,
他们还有人性的话
and they're still people,
我们应该把他们带回去
we should bring 'em in.
像那家伙吗
What, like this guy?
不  那家伙不行
No, not this guy.
我们还没跟丢
We still got a trail.
走吧
Let's go.
快走
Come on.
只是米琼恩和斯宾塞而已
It was just Michonne and Spencer.
他们在干什么
What were they doing?
散步吧  我不知道
Walking. I don't know.
我不想再到外面来了
I don't want to come out here anymore.
好吧
Okay.
卡尔
Carl.
米琼恩在外面  我不能放着不管
Michonne's out here. I'm not leaving it.
不
No.
过来
Come on.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
过来
Come on.
-你在干什么  -你快走
- What are you doing? - Just go.
我们该杀了它
We should kill it.
-回家去  -不
- Go home. - No.
-伊妮德  -这太胡闹了
- Enid. - This is bullshit.
它该死掉才对
It should be dead.
-放开我  -你快走吧
- Let go. - Just leave.
你不能杀它
You're not killing it.
你有什么毛病
What the hell is wrong with you?
你不懂
You wouldn't understand.
你自己说的你不想在外面
You don't want to be out here. You said it.
那就回家去
So go home.
不许动  或许我们不会伤害你
Hold still and maybe we won't hurt you.
没问题
Sure thing.
到此为止了
This is done.
你们有子弹吗
Do you even have any ammo?
好吧
Okay.
为了个卡车就要崩了我吗
You gonna shoot me over a truck?
卡车里有很多食物
There's a lot of food on that truck.
钥匙交出来
The keys, now.
我想你们知道我并不是坏人
I think you know I'm not a bad guy.
是吗
Yeah?
你对我们又了解些什么
What do you know about us?
钥匙给我
Give me the keys.
最后一次警告
This is the last time I'm asking.
该死
Damn it.
你们准备丢下我不管吗
You're gonna leave me here like this?
你们真的打算这么做吗
You're really gonna do that?
绳结不是很紧
The knots aren't that tight.
你应该可以挣脱开的
You should be able to get free...
不过那时我们已经走远了
after we're long gone.
或许我们应该谈谈
Maybe we should talk now.
免了
Nah.
给
Here.
以防你口渴
In case you get thirsty.
再见  混蛋
So long, you prick!
问题还是解决了
Still worked out.
今天依旧是个好日子
Today still is the day.
看那个
Look at that.
是个谷仓
Yeah, a barn.
你听到了吗
You hear that?
我觉得那混蛋在车顶上
I think that son of a bitch is on the roof.
坐稳了
Hold on.
-妈的  -达里尔  达里尔
- Mother-- - Daryl! Daryl!
我们好不容易过个好日子  混蛋
We came to a conclusion, asshole!
我能抓住他
I got him!
过来  你这小混蛋
Come here, you little shit!
蹲下
Duck.
谢了
Thanks.
那是我的枪
That's my gun!
过来
Come here!
你没事吧
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
概率这事
Law of averages.
真是胡扯
That's bullshit, man.
我们去看看那些车  赶紧离开这里
Let's go check them cars, get the hell out of here.
这家伙怎么办
What about the guy?
什么怎么办
What about him?
他救了你
Well, he helped you.
也许吧
Maybe.
他拿枪威胁过你吗
He ever pull a weapon on you?
好吧
Fine.
我们把他放树上
Let's put him up a tree.
你为什么还在这里
Why are you still here?
我很喜欢你妈妈
I liked your mom a lot.
我不希望看到你死
I really don't want you to die.
所以走吧
So, come on.
-回家吧  -我的家人都死了  那不是我家
- Let's go home. - My family's dead. That's not home.
只是我住的地方
It's just where I live.
不止如此
It's more than that.
够了
Hey, enough.
我没事
I'm fine.
你在那儿有你的生活  也许我也会有
You've got a life back there, and maybe I will, too,
但在我考虑那件事之前
but before I can even think about that,
我得先处理别的事
I need to take care of something.
我总得试试
I have to try.
那就让我帮你
So let me help you.
你帮不了
You can't.
卡尔
Carl?
我当晚就以为我看到了她
I thought I saw her that night.
我以为我看到了
I thought I did.
我确实看到了
I did.
我来  我来
I got her. I got her.
这就是我出来的原因
So that's why I was out here.
她留给我一张纸条
She left me a note.
她说我依然没有迷失方向
She said I still knew my way.
我从来就不知道方向在哪
I never knew my way.
你爱你的家人吗
You loved your family?
是的
Yeah.
那你就知道方向
Then you know your way.
是家的方向
It's home.
他们已经死了
They're gone.
我追你走过了大半个树林
I've been out here chasing you all over the woods.
你还有家人
You've still got family,
你还有家
and you've still got a home.
我们走吧
Let's go.
他被重重击中了
He took a pretty hard hit.
得让丹妮斯检查一下
Denise needs to look him over.
是的
Yeah.
你不会那么狠心的
You wouldn't have gone through with it.
你不会丢下他的
You wouldn't have left him.
我会的  放在树上
I would've, right up in a tree.
-我会的  -你不会  我知道
- I would've. - No. I know.
我们一到亚历山大  你就明白了
Almost as soon as we got to Alexandria, you got it.
你看到... 你
You saw-- You...
米琼恩  格伦  你们都试图说服我
and Michonne, Glenn, you all tried to tell me.
所以别嘴硬了
So shut up.
因为我终于肯听你们的了
'Cause I'm finally listening.
看到那颗明星了吗
See that bright one?
对  那是北极星
Yeah, that's the North Star.
位于小熊座的尾部
It's at the end of the Little Dipper.
对
Yeah.
如果你晚上迷路了  只要找到北极星就行
If you get lost at night, just find that star.
今天过得好吗
You have a good day?
我想是吧
I guess so.
我把她抱进去
I'm gonna take her in.
卡尔
Carl.
我看到你做了什么
I saw what you did.
对迪安娜
With Deanna.
是吗
Yeah?
你应该丢下她或者杀了她
You should've left her or killed her.
不  那太蠢了
No, that's stupid.
你不用出去的时候待在外面才是蠢呢
What's stupid is you being out there when you don't have to.
你也一样  你不用...
You did the same thing. You didn't--
你和斯宾塞不用出去的  但你还是去了
You and Spencer didn't have to go out there, but you did.
-那不一样  -一样的
- That's different. - It's not.
我不会把她那样留在外面的
I wasn't gonna leave her out there like that.
你也不会
You wouldn't.
你不会的  我知道
You wouldn't. I know it.
我不能杀掉她
I couldn't kill her.
-为什么不能  -因为...
- Why not? - Because-- be--
你可以杀掉她的
You could've killed her.
不  我不能  我不想那么做
No, I couldn't. I wouldn't.
你以为在外面是玩游戏吗
Were you playing some sort of game out there?
-难道你以为...  -不是
- Did you think that-- - No!
那为什么
Then why?
因为应该由一个爱她的人来做
Because it should be someone who loved her,
她的家人  我也会为你做同样的事
someone who's family, and I-- I'd do it for you.
我会的
I would.
过来
Come here.
我也是
Me, too.
(欢迎来到亚历山大安全区  迷途者的天堂  掠夺者的地狱)
知道吗  我在想...
You know, I was thinking...
我们出发去采石场前
back before we went out to the quarry.
雷吉和皮特那事之后的早上
The morning after Reg and Pete.
你说我们不应该再寻找人类了
You said we shouldn't be looking for people no more.
你是对的
You were right.
不
No...
我错了
I was wrong.
你是对的
You were right.
-抱歉吵醒你们  -他是谁
- Sorry to wake you up. - Who is this?
快点  他很沉
Come on, man, he's heavy.
你的饮料  泡汤了
Oh, that thing, uh, didn't work out.
是这个混蛋的错  抱歉
It's this asshole's fault. Sorry.
把他放在床上
Lay him on the bed.
好  检查一下他
All right, take a look at him.
但他不会久留
He ain't staying, though.
(你受伤了  我们带你来了这里  你很安全  保重  瑞克)
再看看吧
We'll see.
我们俩出去确实挺蠢的  不是吗
It is pretty stupid of us to go out there, isn't it?
是啊
Yep.
-明天再来一次  -好
- Do it again tomorrow? - Yep.
让开
Move.
你好
Hey.
她在睡梦中练习呢
She's practicing in her sleep.
是啊
Yeah.
回家真好
It's good to be home.
可不是么
Yeah, you're telling me.
达里尔在哪里
Where's Daryl?
他在看守一个人
Watching over a guy
之后会有人接替他
till some other guy can take over.
你们找到了一个人
You found a guy?
疯狂的一天
Crazy day.
你想说说吗
You wanna talk about it?
现在不想
No, not right now.
我只想放松一会儿
I just want to turn my brain off for a minute.
你想跟我说说你的一天吗
You wanna tell me about your day?
不
No.
我也一样
Same thing.
怎么  你也找到人了
What, you found a guy?
不是人
Not a guy.
好吧
Oh...
给你带了样东西
Got you something.
这是牙膏的替代品吗
Is this instead of the toothpaste?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
我本来给你搞了一箱牙膏
Well, I do have a crate of toothpaste for you.
现在沉到了湖底
It's currently at the bottom of a lake.
-你今天过得真刺激  -是啊
- Oh, so you had a day. - Yeah...
都是为了你的口腔卫生
all on account of your dental hygiene.
吃你的薄荷糖吧
Have your mints.
等等
Wait-- wait a minute.
好
Okay.
瑞克
Rick.
瑞克  醒醒
Rick, wake up.
我们应该谈谈
We should talk.